Finding Aid for Programs for Educational Opportunity (University of Michigan) records, 1969-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project for the Fair Administration of School Discipline (PFASD)
  - Public Schools
    - Detroit
      - "Detroit Discipline Data for the Second Semester," 1975-1976 (Box 7)
      - Field Activities Reports 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Ecourse
      - Code of Behavior and Rights Statements circa 1970 (Box 8)
    - Flint
      - Code of Behavior and Rights Statements 1971-1972 (Box 8)
    - Grand Blanc
      - Code of Behavior and Rights Statements, c1970 (Box 8)
    - Grand Rapids
      - Code of Behavior and Rights Statements 1971 (Box 8)
    - Highland Park
      - Code of Behavior and Rights Statements circa 1970 (Box 8)
      - Discipline Procedures manual (Box 8)
      - Field Activities Reports 1977 (Box 8)
    - Jackson
      - Code of Behavior and Rights Statements circa 1970 (Box 8)
      - Field Activities Reports 1978-1980, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Lansing
      - "Assessment of Selected Dimensions of the Discipline Process at Building Ten, District C," 1980
        - Final Report (Box 8)
        - Executive Summary (Box 8)
      - "Assessment of Selected Dimensions of the Discipline Process at Building Twelve, District C, Final Report" circa 1980 (Box 8)
      - "Assessment of Selected Dimensions of the Discipline Process at Building Thirteen, District C, Final Report," circa 1980 (Box 8)
      - Attendance Report 1978 (Box 8)
      - Code of Behavior and Rights Statements 1972 (Box 8)
      - Code of Conduct 1975 (Box 8)
      - Discipline Measures circa 1978 (Box 8)
      - "Dwight Rich Discipline System Flow Chart," 1980 (Box 8)
      - Field Activities reports 1977-1980, 5 folders (Box 8)
      - Preliminary Discipline Assessment of Hill High School 1978-1979 (Box 8)
      - Proposed Technical Assistance Plan, FY 1980-1982 (Box 8)
      - Recommendations 1980 (Box 8)
      - Suspended Students, Characteristics of 1977 (Box 8)
    - Pontiac
      - Codes of Behavior and Rights Statements 1972 (Box 8)
      - Field Activities Reports 1977-1978 (Box 8)
    - Rochester
      - Codes of Behavior and Rights Statements 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - Southfield
      - Codes of Behavior and Rights Statements 1971 (Box 8)
    - "Assessment of Responsibility for Student Discipline," undated (Box 8)
    - "Assessing Disproportionate Minority Discipline: An Examination of a Recently Desegregated Middle School," 1/1978 (Box 8)
    - "Assessing Disproportionate Minority Suspensions: A High School Case Study," 2/1980
      - Final Report circa 1980 (Box 8)
      - Executive Summary circa 1980 (Box 8)
    - "Considerations for Selecting Program Strategies," 2/1980 (Box 8)
    - "Discipline Task Force Activities," undated (Box 8)
    - "Earning through Learning to Cooperate, (ELC)" 1/1979 (Box 8)
    - "Feedback Evaluation Design: A Process Model," 1/1979 (Box 8)
    - "Model for the Development of Policies Governing Student Rights and Responsibilities," undated (Box 8)
    - "Phase I Research Reports of PFASD," 5/1976, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - "Phase II Implementation Plans of PFASD", 2 folders (Box 9)
    - "Proposal for Establishment of PFASD", 2 folders (Box 9)
    - "School Four, Phase I Research Report" 1979, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - "Student Leadership Training Retreat Summary Report," 1979 (Box 9)
  - Workshops
    - "Building Class Rules," 1978
      - General (Box 9)
      - Chronology (Box 9)
      - Notes (Box 9)
      - Planning Materials, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Regulations (Box 9)
    - "Options for Classroom Management," 1978 (Box 9)
    - "Student Diversity, Adolescent Development, and Discipline Management," 5/79, 2 folders (Box 9)
- Public School
  The Public Schools series (2.25 feet) covers the years 1978-1980. The series contains varied information on specific schools. Researchers should note the existence of specific information on public schools in other series such as Desegregation and PFASD. A large amount of material in the Public Schools series focuses on Ann Arbor. School-specific task forces, surveys, reports, committees, and correspondence are included within Ann Arbor, while the rest of the series contains only year end reports of schools.
  - Ann Arbor
    - Miscellaneous 1975-1985 (Box 9)
    - Alternative Program
      - 1974 (Box 9)
      - 1975-1978 (Box 9)
    - Black Curriculum Commission 1971 (Box 9)
    - Black Employees Association 1974, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Black English Court Case (Box 9)
    - Black Youth Task Force 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Board of Education
      - 1977-1983 (Box 9)
      - 1984 (Box 9)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 9)
    - Community Survey
      - 1986-1987 (Box 9)
      - Final Report 1987 (Box 9)
      - History 1983-1987 (Box 9)
      - Proposal 1987 (Box 9)
    - "Curriculum and Instructional Strategies for Improving Educational Opportunities (Task Force)," 1980 (Box 9)
    - Dicken School Task Force 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Equal Education Opportunity Analysis (EEO) 1978 (Box 9)
    - Excellence, Committee on 1985-1987 (Box 9)
    - Gender and Ethnic Equity Assessment 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Graduation Requirements Committee 1971-1973 (Box 9)
    - Haisley Elementary School Achievement Motivation Program In Service Training 1974, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Human Relations 1970-1974 (Box 10)
    - "Improving Educational Opportunities and Improving Racial Balance," 1980 (Box 10)
    - "Increasing Your Teaching Effectiveness," 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Instructional Skills for Effective Teaching (ISET) 1982-1983 (Box 10)
    - Leadership Development Program 1984 (Box 10)
    - Leadership Development Seminar 1983 (Box 10)
    - Martin Luther King Commemoration 1980-1984 (Box 10)
    - McPherson, R. Bruce (Superintendent) 1971-1972 (Box 10)
    - Model Cities Program 1971-1973 (Box 10)
    - Multi-Ethnic Curriculum, Committee on 1971 (Box 10)
    - Potts, Robert (Human Relations Ombudsman)
      - 1971-1973 (Box 10)
      - 1974 (Box 10)
      - 1975 (Box 10)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 10)
      - Memos 1972-1974 (Box 10)
    - Racial Balance, Citizens' Advisory Committee on 1979, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Racism, Committee on 1971-1972 (Box 10)
    - Reorganization Monitoring Committee 1986-1987 (Box 10)
    - Scarlett Cluster (Staff In-Service) 1974 (Box 10)
    - Sex and Race Equity Assessment 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Staff Development
      - 1975-1978 (Box 10)
      - 1980-1985 (Box 10)
    - Statistical Data of Staff and Students
      - 1977-1981 (Box 10)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 10)
    - Title IX Monitoring Committee 1975 (Box 10)
    - Year End Report 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Benton Harbor
    - Year End Report 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Cass Technical
    - Needs Assessment (Box 10)
    - "A Brief Preliminary Report," 1978 (Box 10)
    - "Methodology, Findings, Conclusions, Recommendations, and Executive Summary," 1978 (Box 10)
  - Cherry Hill
    - Year End Report 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Detroit
    - School Community Relations Program, Evaluation of 1980 (Box 10)
    - Sex Equity Pilot 1983 (Box 10)
    - Year End Report
      - 1978-1979 (Box 10)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 10)
  - Dowagiac Union
    - Year End Report 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Ferndale
    - Year End Report 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - Flint
    - Miscellaneous 1975-1986 (Box 11)
    - Year End Report
      - 1978-1979 (Box 11)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - Grand Rapids
    - Miscellaneous 1974-1982 (Box 11)
    - Year End Report 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Kalamazoo
    - Year End Report
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - Lansing
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1975-1977 (Box 11)
      - 1979-1982 (Box 11)
    - Year End Report
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - Mount Clemens
    - Year End Report 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - Pontiac
    - Year End Report
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - Three Rivers Community
    - Year End Report 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Willow Run
    - Miscellaneous 1975-1981 (Box 11)
  - Ypsilanti
    - Miscellaneous 1976-1980 (Box 11)
    - Year End Report
      - 1978-1979 (Box 11)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files series (.5 feet) spans the years 1971-1984. The series comprises information on various national and university programs and associations and how they related to PEO. Records concern the National Institute of Education, the Trotter House, the United Negro Fund, Inc., and the School of Social Work, in addition to others. Information on the engineering program and the recruitment of minorities, the Center for Occupational and Personalized Education, Inc. (COPE), the National Alliance of Black School Educators, and the Multi-Cultural Program are well represented.
  - Black Caucus (School of Education) 1971-1973, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Bush Program in Child Development and Social Policy 1982 (Box 11)
  - COPE (Center for Occupational and Personalized Education, Inc.)
    - 1975-1977, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - 1979 (Box 11)
  - Division Chairperson 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Engineering Program 1981-1982, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Ethnic Heritage Resources 1978-1982 (Box 11)
  - Multi-Cultural Program 1973-1978, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - National Alliance of Black School Educators 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - National Diffusion Network 1978, 1980 (Box 11)
  - National Institute of Education 1973, 1980 (Box 11)
  - New Detroit, Inc. 1974-1982 (Box 12)
  - Social Work Internships 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Social Work School 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Student Advocacy Center 1976-1977 (Box 12)
  - Television Center (Alma Smith) 1979 (Box 12)
  - Trotter House (Bulah Sanderson) 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - United Negro Fund, Inc. 1981 (Box 12)
  - Urban Grant Program 1980
- Administrative
  The Administrative series (1.0 linear feet) spans the years 1971-1996 and contains budgets, meeting minutes and other organizational material. Some correspondence and annual reports are also included.
  - Cabinet 1980 (Box 12)
  - Committees
    - Staff Development 1978-1980 (Box 12)
    - Validation 1983 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence 1986-1989 (Box 12)
  - Director's Files 1978-1987, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Liaison Operating Plan FY 1982 (Box 12)
  - Meeting Minutes
    - Clerical 1987 (Box 12)
    - Staff 1983-1996, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Manual 1976 (Box 12)
  - Organizational Structure undated (Box 12)
  - Reports
    - Final FY 1972 (Box 12)
    - Final FY 1974 (Box 12)
    - Final FY 1976 (Box 13)
    - Final Technical Report 1971-1973 (Box 13)
    - Quarterly 1974-1977, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Quarterly 1978 (Box 13)
    - Year End Report 1989-1990 (Box 13)
- Conferences
  The Conferences series (.5 linear feet) consists of material from 1974 to 1992. It contains information on education conferences which PEO either sponsored or in which it was a major participant.
  - Afrocentric Educational Academy 1991 (Box 13)
  - Compliance Related Training Materials 1980 (Box 13)
  - Connection Center 1991 (Box 13)
  - Critical Issues in Race, Gender, and National Origin Equity 1992 (Box 13)
  - Equity and School of Choice 1991 (Box 13)
  - Equity Works 1993 (Box 13)
  - Goals 2000 Conference, 1994 (Box 13)
  - Michigan White House Conference 1980 (Box 13)
  - Multi-Ethnic Workshops 1975, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - National Alliance of Black Superintendents 1982 (Box 13)
  - National Collation for Sex Equity in Education 1989 (Box 13)
  - National Desegregation Assistance Center Coordination 1978-1980 (Box 13)
  - Participating Parents for Progress 1986-1987 (Box 13)
  - Reading is More than Facts 1978 (Box 13)
  - Reference Guide to Conference Material 1979 (Box 13)
  - Regional Equity Network 1989 (Box 13)
  - PEO Retreat 1980 (Box 13)
  - Take it Home: Some Multicultural Approaches to Math and Reading 1978 (Box 13)
  - Title IV Desegregation Program 1989 (Box 13)
  - Title IX Conference 1977 (Box 13)
  - Title IX Roundtable Minority Women 1982 (Box 13)
  - Writing Math Strategies 1978 (Box 13)
- Center for Sex Equity in Schools (CSES)
  The Center for Sex Equity in Schools (CSES) (1 linear feet) covers the years 1978-1990. It contains grant proposals and reports for the sex desegregation efforts of PEO. This series contains material relating to the central functioning of the center including correspondence with the U.S. Department of Education. Materials detailing services to individual school districts are arranged alphabetically in the Public Schools series. In the materials CSES is sometimes called a Sex Desegregation Assistance Center.
  - Grant Proposals
    - FY 1978, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - FY 1982, 2 volumes (Box 14)
    - FY 1983, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - FY 1984-FY 1987, 5 folders (Box 14)
    - 1987-1990 (Box 14)
  - Final Reports
    - June 1982 (Box 14)
    - July 1982-August 1984, 2 volumes (Box 14)
- Desegregation Assistance Center (DAC)
  The Desegregation Assistance Center (DAC) (3.3 linear feet) is the largest series in the accession and spans 1972-1993. It contains grant proposals and correspondence regarding the efforts of PEO to facilitate race desegregation. This series contains material relating to the central functioning of the center including correspondence with the U.S. Department of Education. Materials detailing services to individual school districts are arranged alphabetically in the Public Schools series. The DAC is sometimes referred to as a Race Desegregation Assistance Center and other times as a General Desegregation Assistance Center. Material relating to sex desegregation are in the Center for Sex Equity in Schools series.
  - Grant Proposals
    - Application for Human Subjects Review 1983 (Box 14)
    - Achieving Equity Based Education through Innovation and Organizational Change 1982, 2 volumes (Box 14)
    - FY 1974, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - FY 1975, 5 folders (Box 15)
    - FY 1976, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - FY 1977, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - FY 1978, 2 volumes (Box 15)
    - FY 1979, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - FY 1980-FY 1981 (Box 15)
    - FY 1982, 2 volumes (Box 16)
    - May 1982 (Box 16)
    - FY 1983 (Box 16)
    - FY 1984, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - FY 1985 (Box 16)
    - FY 1986 (Box 16)
    - FY 1987, 2 volumes; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - FY 1989 (Box 16)
    - 1987-1990 (Box 16)
    - 1990-1993, 2 volumes (Box 17)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 17)
    - Multicultural Resource Center 1990-1992, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Reports
    - Equity Profiles in Public Education: Education Indicators and Expressed Needs for Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota and Wisconsin 1988 (Box 17)
    - Final
      - FY 1972 (Box 17)
      - FY 1977, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - FY 1979 (Box 17)
      - FY 1980 (Box 17)
      - FY 1981 (Box 17)
      - FY 1982, 4 folders (Box 17)
      - 1982-1984, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Final Research Report 1976 (Box 17)
- Project for the Fair Administration of School Discipline (PFASD)
  - Grant Proposals
    The Project for Fair Administration of School Discipline (PFASD) (.3 linear feet) cover 1976-1980. It contains grant proposals for the project as well as the 1976 final report.
    - FY 1976 (Box 18)
    - FY 1977, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - 1976-1978 (Box 18)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 18)
  - Final Report 1976 (Box 18)
- Public Schools
  Public Schools (2 linear ft) is a large series which spans the years 1976-1990. The series contains information on the assistance provided to school districts mostly in Indiana, Illinois, Michigan, Ohio and Wisconsin. The series contains material regarding both the CSES and the race desegregation efforts of PEO. Some school districts participated in both programs while others participated in just one or the other. The series consists largely of year end reports and some correspondence.
  - Ann Arbor Public Schools
    - Center for Sex Equity in Schools (CSES)
      - Year End Report, 1984/1985-1985/1986 (Box 18)
    - Programs for Educational Opportunity (PEO)
      - Year End Reports
        - 1976-1977 (Box 18)
        - 1980/1981-1981/1982 (Box 18)
  - Aurora East
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1987/188 (Box 18)
  - Brainerd Aviti
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1986-1987 (Box 18)
  - Bridgeport-Spaulding
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1987 (Box 18)
  - Bridgeport CT.
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1981 (Box 18)
      - Reports 1980-1981 (Box 18)
  - Buena Vista
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Cherry Hill School District
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Chicago Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1987-1988 (Box 18)
  - Cleveland Heights-University Heights
    - CSES
      - Year End Report, 1984/1985-1985/1986 (Box 18)
  - Cleveland Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1985/1986-1986/1987 (Box 18)
    - PEO
      - Annual Report 1988-1989 (Box 18)
      - Design, Development, Implementation, Analysis and Reporting of the Cleveland City School Climate Survey Proposal 1992 (Box 18)
      - Year End Report 1987-1988 (Box 18)
  - Coloma Community Schools
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1981-1982 (Box 18)
  - Detroit Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Sex Equity Pilot 1983 (Box 18)
      - Year End Report 1985-1986 (Box 18)
    - PEO
      - Annual Report 1982-1983 (Box 18)
      - Correspondence 1987 (Box 18)
      - Expulsion Study 1982-1986 (Box 18)
      - Status and Summary of PEO Service Interventions 1983-1984 (Box 18)
      - Technical Assistance Plan 1983-1984 (Box 18)
      - Year End Report, 1985/1986-1987/1988, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Duluth Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - Eden Prairie Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Ecourse
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1976-1977 (Box 19)
  - Ferndale Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Flint Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Multicultural Education in Four Flint Community High Schools 1980 (Box 19)
  - Green Bay Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Year End Report, 1985/1986-1987/1988, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Indiana Department of Education
    - CSES
      - Year End Report, 1985/1986-1986/1987 (2 folders (Box 19)
    - PEO
      - Annual Report 1989-1990 (Box 19)
  - Indianapolis Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Annual Report 1989-1990 (Box 19)
  - Kalamazoo School District
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Kenosha Unified School District Number 1
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1985-1986 (Box 19)
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1985/1986-1986/1987, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - La Crescent Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Year End Report, 1985/1986-1986/1987, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Lansing School District
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Lawrence Township Indiana
    - CSES
      - Year End Report, 1984/1985-1986/1987, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Madison Metropolitan Schools
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1979-1980 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report 1979-1980 (Box 19)
  - Michigan Department of Education
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1979 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Milwaukee Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1981-1982 (Box 19)
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1980-1981 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report 1979-1980 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report, 1984/1985-1987/1988, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Minneapolis Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Annual Report 1989-1990 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report, 1984/1985-1986/1987, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Minnesota Department of Education
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1978-1980 (Box 19)
      - Equals Minnesota Annual Report 1989-1990 (Box 19)
  - Monticello Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Year End Report, 1984/1985-1985/1986, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Northfield, MN. School District
    - CSES
      - Annual Report 1986 (Box 19)
  - Nicolette
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1979 (Box 19)
  - Oak Park Schools
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Ohio Department of Education
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1987-1988 (Box 19)
  - Pontiac Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Racine
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1978-1980 (Box 19)
  - Robinsdale Independent School District
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1985-1986 (Box 19)
    - PEO
      - Annual Report 1989-1990 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report, 1985/1986-1986/1987, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Rochester Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Annual Report 1989-1990 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report 1985-1986 (Box 19)
  - Saint Paul Independent School District
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1981-1982 (Box 19)
  - Saint Paul Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1984/1985-1986/1987, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - PEO
      - Annual Report 1989-1990 (Box 19)
      - Correspondence 1974-1981 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report 1979-1980 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report 1984-1985 (Box 19)
      - Year End Report 1986-1987 (Box 19)
  - Shorewood Schools
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1978 (Box 19)
  - Willow Run Public Schools
    - PEO
      - Year End Report 1976-1977 (Box 20)
  - Winona Public Schools
    - CSES
      - Year End Report 1986-1987 (Box 20)
  - Wisconsin Department of Public Instruction
    - PEO
      - Correspondence 1979-1988 (Box 20)
      - Year End Report 1985-1986 (Box 20)
  - Ypsilanti School District
    - PEO
      - Year End Report
        - 1975-1976 (Box 20)
        - 1985/1986-1987/1988, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Zumbrota Public Schools
    - Correspondence 1982-1985 (Box 20)
    - Year End Report, 1984/1985-1986/1987, 2 folders (Box 20)
- Topical Files
  The Topical Files (.3 linear feet) series is a small series dating from 1978 to 1995. It contains miscellaneous reports and other materials concerning education and in particular minority education.
  - The Common Challenge of 5 Urban School Districts and the Creation of the Urban Educational Alliance 1985 (Box 20)
  - Handbook of Training Activities to Combat Sexism in Education undated (Box 20)
  - Identifying and Utilizing Resources for School Desegregation 1979 (Box 20)
  - Nondiscriminatory Employment Decision Making in Public Schools undated (Box 20)
  - Results from the Superintendents Survey 1986 (Box 20)
  - The Status of Desegregation in Michigan 1978, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Strengthening the Leadership Skills of Special Education Faculty Members of Historically Black Colleges 1989 (Box 20)
  - Technical Assistance Center 1989-1995
- Programs
  Programs (.8 linear feet) is the largest series in this accession, and it contains documents, forms, handouts, and photographs from the Family Math, Family Science, Middle School Family Math, and Playtime is Science programs. The series spans 1981 to 2002, but the years 1994-2002 are best represented. Records are arranged alphabetically by program, with materials concerning each program arranged chronologically. The series is most useful for documenting "Leadership Workshops," where teachers were trained to run the programs in their schools.
  - Detroit Summer Institute 1995-1997 (Box 21)
  - Equals 1983-1986, 1988 (Box 21)
  - Equals Sites' Meetings 1991-1994 (Box 21)
  - Families Achieving New Standards (FANS) 1999-2001 (Box 21)
  - Family Math
    - Burns Park School 1993 (Box 21)
    - Materials from Berkeley 1991 (Box 21)
    - Public Relations 1990, 1994-2001 (Box 21)
    - Requests 2003-2004 (Box 21)
  - Family Math and Playtime is Science Leadership Workshop 1999 (Box 21)
  - Family Math and Science 2001-2003 (Box 21)
  - Family Math Leadership Workshop, Photographs 1988 (Box 21)
  - Family Math Leadership Workshop 1990, 1992-2002, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Family Math Parent Meeting 2001 (Box 21)
  - Family Math Reunion 1994-2002, 6 folders (Box 21)
  - Family Math Training-of-Trainers Workshop 1993 (Box 21)
  - Family Science (Pilot) 1989-1990 (Box 21)
  - Family Science, Introduction to 2002 (Box 21)